we're going to do number
10 up there there you
go all right number 10 uh what was
number 10 for zero dollars
for yeah it's called take
responsibility and I'm gonna read the
whole thing to you it's kind of long
means uh you do giving and
taking you take other people's
problem
Happ then
says then you should pause and ask
yourself did it work this is the
you know I was trying to take other
people's
problem and I was trying to give other
people my
happiness which is the same as love and
comp try to give them good
things try to take away their
problem that's eight and
N then 10 is
did it work
or means no it didn't
work know I tried to take away other
people's
problem I tried to give them my
happiness did it work you know this
breath it
says did not directly I could not
directly do
it after 19 years
of on the
subway was the people on the subway
happier and the answer is
no so is it a waste of
time then you have to
decide and this is a very beautiful
practice for your whole
life it's called FL
sayam
means and by the way everything you do
in your lifeam is
useful means I don't care if nobody
helps me I'm gonna do
it it's like cleaning up this place
after the
[Music]
talk suddenly everybody
disappears and then means I don't
care I'll take care of
it and it's a very beautiful state of
mind if you can use
this to
reach then the rest of your life is
really
fun and it's the
decision that I will take care of making
this happen I don't care if nobody helps
me I think in my own
life I I went a little bit too
far and uh I I decided nobody's gonna
help me
anyway so I just ignore
everybody and try to make things
happen
and I think that's not
helpy means if you help me welcome I
love you let's do
it but if you run away or you don't have
time then okay I'll take
care but I think there's a kind
of you're like you guys know help me
anyway I'll do it
myself that's not a good
thing I
think please help
me I'll help you help me I'll have chur
ready but if you're too
busy can't help me listen I'm gonna do
this thing
and I I encourage the old man
of 7 year old
man I tell you it's a very beautiful
skill to to decide if you don't help me
I do it
[Music]
myself so I encourage you to
develop
I will make this good thing
Happ
that's all right number
11 by the way comes why it's so long
number
10 it means uh look at what's happening
around
you good wishes are not
enough oh I give you my
happiness oh I take away your
trouble oh I give you
my then everyone looks the
same then it's not enough just to do
the then you have to do the
work it's nice to breathe on people but
it's not enough
this is just a motivation key is just to
improve your
motivation then you have to do the
work and that's number
10 all of these sound hard and all of
these are really
fun I'm sorry once you walk into this
class you're going to be a b
and bodh saas work their whole life for
other
people if you didn't want to be a bodh
SAA you shouldn't have come
here now you're
stuck now you have to be a
body and at the beginning it feels like
too much
work
what's a
buh that's number
11 okay and number 11 is okay I'll take
responsibility not just for my family
not just for my
job I take responsibility for my country
for my world and by the way for all the
other worlds why
not
okay I'll take
responsibility and that's number
11 okay I will personally make sure
everyone is
happy we talk a lot about seeing
emptiness
directly in DCI we call it touching the
diamond
world I can tell you uh I don't know
this cell phone it comes from seeds in
my
mind this was not made in a foxcom
factory in
Shanghai this was made from your
seeds you created this
thing you made this thing
happen then uh that's understanding of
dependent origination cause and
effect what is
dependence half of
Buddhism everything's coming from that's
basically everything's coming from
you this was not made in a
factory your mental seeds made the
factory
also you you made this thing what's the
opposite of that
there's nothing else in the
world everything was made by
you also
time is made by your
seet when you're making out with your
girlfriend in high
school like me and Veronica 53 years
ago we went to the drive-in
movie
we get borrow my mother's station wagon
because it has a big
vacine by the way we're just kissing
okay this guy is suddenly there's a guy
banging on the
window he says put roll down your
window there security guard you
know he says you guys you got to go
home he said why the movie just
started he said the goddamn movie End
two hours
ago you guys aren't watching the
movie you know they we look the whole
place is empty you
know it means when you're having fun the
time goes very
fun Alison and Stanley came with me
recently I had a surgery on a
te that guy he actually sat on my chest
he's
[Music]
like then I thought it must be about
three hours
[Music]
you then it was like not not that right
it's like half an
hour so
time is also coming from your
feet and time can go faster and time can
go
slower and space is coming from
this so time and space is
a it's a
perception it's
subjective okay it's not
objective there's not 60 minutes in an
hour and there's I asked my boss he's
from
Israel I said uh how many grams in a
kilogram he said only American will ask
this
question kilo means 1,000 kilog is a th
understand
but it's not
true there's not a thousand met in a
kilometer it depends on Einstein said
that
Einstein it's very very beautiful
Einstein and you knowa fit together
perfect Einstein said time and space
will change according to your
conceptions Einstein
there's a little tiny planet called
Mercury it's the smallest
one it's very close to the
Sun it goes very fast around the
Sun Mercury is the name of some Roman or
Greek the fastest of the flying
[Music]
gods and Einstein
said uh Mercury is so close to the
Sun that the the light from
Mercury when when the sun is
here and the Earth is
here and Mercury goes around the
Sun and when it first comes out and you
can see it from the
earth that
light is it's matter it's a kind of
physical
matter when little physical matter gets
near big physical matter the thing falls
down the Earth is fatter than my
iPhone if I let go the Earth will not
fall out the phone will fall
down light from
Mercury when it when Mercury comes out
from behind the
sun and the light is coming to
us that light has a little bit of
weight and the Sun's gravity will pull
the light towards the
Sun so the light from Mercury doesn't
come
Direct it goes It goes a little bit
towards the Sun and then comes to
me and that takes
longer when you see mercury in a
telescope you are seeing yesterday's
Mercury you are not seeing today's
Mercury when you look in a telescope you
are time
traveling
what you are seeing is what was there
yesterday because the light was bent and
the light took longer to reach
[Music]
you when you see the light from
gish's special
hair it also takes some time you are
never seeing Gesa you are seeing gisha
as he was one second
ago in the driv
movie making out with your
girlfriend in the dentist
chair when you are looking at
Mercury time is
flexible time is coming from
you why gar why you you supposed to be
teaching
toer
when you touch the diamond
world when you see emptiness
directly for like 24
hours you are able to change
time and you are able to change
space and on that
day you will meet every person
in the
UN
to one by one okay how many
people there's no
number there's always one more after
that it's like work you know there's
always one more after
done okay when you trying to meet
everybody in the
universe there's always one more behind
that
one and there's no end no and that's
infinite yes but if time is coming from
you you can meet everybody in the
universe in 20
minutes on the day that you touch
emptiness
directly you get power to change
time
and you can meet every living being face
to
face it goes like
this hi what's your
name I am Martian number
55 oh nice to meet
you how you doing life is hard
sometimes you know what number 55 from
Mars I'm going to take take care of your
personally you don't have to worry about
anything number
10 I'll take care of
[Music]
it I'm having difficult life on
Mars hey you met the right
man or the right
woman take care personally I'll take
care of
you are we
good yes very
good okay see you
later then the next person
comes billions and billions of people in
[Music]
20 and that's
real so that's the direct experience of
number
11 it's not a wish
it's not an
intention it's not a
prayer you meet every living being
directly and you have a small
chat you good now very difficult on my
plan I'm here man I've
gotam I'm used to it
I'll take care of
it you go back to your planet and relax
everything like thank
you and you do that with a billion
billion people in in 20
minutes that's number
11 that's a real body who has seen
EMP we
call
that to be the to be a super
B you have to touch emptiness
directly because you can't meet and
comfort every living being if you cannot
change
time okay so you have to touch
that's where emptiness needs
compassion you can't take care of
everybody unless you can mess around
with
time there's more parents in our Mexico
group than in any group in the whole
world that means there's more really
busy people in this room than anywhere
else and if you're a mom or overwork
Dad wouldn't it be nice to have 30 hours
a day or 48 hours a
day when you really understand
emptiness you can do
it ask me how you how you do we have
200,000
students how you have
time mess with the
seeds make more
time okay and you can do
it that's why it's so important to study
emptiness if you want to be
a because emptiness means you can
manipulate them
it's a necessary job skill
for that's
why when we finish this
section we going to do emptiness for
five
years so you can mess with time and
SP then you can be a real
bodh kind of be the ultimate mom or dad
you have to be in two places at the same
[Music]
time that's why we have to study
emptiness after we do
this okay Tim I'm ready to start the
class that was the review of the
11 uh how much time I got Timothy
till
9 10 all right okay half
on
uh I'm going to start introducing to you
Edom i i
m it means idea image idea
image uh in the
program uh we do 25
years study uh it's very
difficult and three four hours every day
we have to go to
[Music]
debate
like that we have to do it like that
from
memory you cannot take the book into the
de my first day I took a book in the
debate ground oh my
[Music]
God they like threw me
out no books in the debate
ground so how do you remember all this
stuff we cheat we use
pictures we use Mental
pictures so I'm going to teach you this
system and so we're GNA start using
pictures this week's class has 50
pictures if you remember what the
picture is about you don't have to
memorize the
book
so I'm going to start showing you
pictures each picture has a
meaning okay you just have to remember
the
meaning starting
tomorrow I will ask you what's this
picture what's the
meaning if you explain it maybe you get
a
$100 if you cannot maybe you pay
$100 sound good no I'm just
kidding okay but we're gonna learn how
to think how to remember the class from
the
pictures okay here's the first picture
you guys
ready uh I saw a movie on the
airplane so it's a 12 hour flight to
Japan
and uh I always watch a
movie I work for like eight hours and
then I get weird and I have to watch a
movie and there was a very sad
movie they were making a documentary
about this
guy and he's a famous mot Motocross
guy so they were following him and they
were filming
him and in the in the film he had an
accident and he broke his
spine so like today he's the most famous
motorcycle rider in the world every
young lady wants to meet
him and then in the evening he cannot he
cannot go to
poop
he's pooping in his own
bed for the rest of his
life you cannot reattach his
spine then they they they had many
discussions with him in the
movie and something happened to
him and here's the story from
Shanta you guys got it it's called it's
page 322 you got
it
yeah means Master
Shan 1,300 years
ago in the book called bodh way of
life which is
50% how to be a nice person and 50%
emptiness
why if you want to be a really nice
person you have to be able to change
time and
space you have to be able to do 48 hours
of work in 24
hours so you got to understand emptiness
that you want to be a
bod okay and what he said in his
[Music]
book that's his
advice when you break your spine riding
your
motorcycle try to
appreciate sorry try to appreciate
appreciate all the good stuff that's
just
happened okay when you when you have a
terrible tragedy in your
life try to understand one
thing it's going to smash your
pride no no girls are chasing him
anymore because the main relationship is
to wipe his
bottle nobody's no girls are chasing him
now and he's he's his head is straight
his mind is
clear like he went through some terrible
months of suffering and
disappointment unha
and now he's
extremely beautiful
person you know he changed his
life the suffering changed his
life so the idea is if you want to be a
bodh if you're lucky you will break his
SP and then you you will really have
compassion for other
people
and if he was just famous his whole life
and made lots of money he he would never
find
compassion so the whole argument of the
book at this
moment number
one you should you should be happy when
disasters happen in your
life they make you a better person
you should pray that disasters happen in
your
life if you really want to be
a and then that's the first
half uh when you break your own spine
suddenly you notice all the other people
who have spine
problems a couple weeks ago I I I was
coming back from
Japan I tripped in the
passport I fell
down and I uh I kind of broke a bone in
my
foot I was with s and Tim
right and I'm like I can't
walk and they're like okay let's get a
wheelchair
you and I'm like oh no I don't want to
be like all those grandpas and
Grandma so I tried to walk for like half
an hour you
know with a broken
foot then I'm like you know what Tim
I'll take the
wheelchair and then they're just driving
me around
real
okay what's the only place in the world
where people treat me like a
[Music]
llama United
Airlines United Airlines you know
there's gold platinum silver all
diamond there's a special level it's a
secret
level and the board of direct directors
of United Airlines has to
vote and then they call you they say you
are global Service they call Global
[Music]
Service here's how you know you are
global
Service I got off the airplane in San
Francisco I have to get on the airplane
to
Phoenix Pho there's a guy with a sign Mr
roach I'm Mr Roach is there a
problem he says I'm your limousine
driver and I'm like but I'm not stopping
in San Francisco I'm going to
Phoenix Pho yeah I know I'm the
limousine driver to your next
airplane then I'm like how far is it to
the next
airplane
he said it's right
there I said you're going to drive me in
a limousine to the next
game he said yeah it's right downstairs
you come down the stairs get in the
limousine we drive you to the airplane
you go
up I'm like you know what I'll just
walk there's a Starbucks
also then he's like well congratulations
you are Global you are global Service
now he start to prostrate I said no it's
okay no I'm
kidding but uh global Service with a
wheelchair they're like Mr Ro are you
okay I push your
wheelchair and then suddenly I feel like
those old people in the airplane you
know like don't get out of the chair
just sit there I'm like
okay and it's so good for your
pride that's the
idea when things happen to
you when you
fail you get fired from your
job you get fired from your
marriage then suddenly your pride relax
a little
bit and so it's good for
us those
disasters when you have a
disaster try to
think now I'm not so proud about Glo
global
Service now they're pushing me in the
whe
[Music]
chair and then you get in English we say
you get more real you become a more
genuine
person nin came you start to sympathize
with the other people in the
wheelchair I never noticed how many
people are in the wheelchair in the
airport now I feel like P hey
[Laughter]
chocolate like yeah man
then suddenly you notice all the people
in the
wheelchair it's good for your
heart to have some good
disasters so next time you have a
disaster in your
family or your job you could say
yay now I'm a
better now I really understand all the
people in the real chch
so when you have a problem be feel like
lucky should feel like
unlucky then he says
dig which means once you have a
disaster you will be more careful not to
hurt other people because that's gon
that's why you
only
that's why you broke your
foot you must have Hur
from so then after you get to the
wheelchair you have to be it makes you
more careful not to do bad things to
other
people then if you get more
trouble more
problems your compassion gets better and
better
you don't have to go to Diamond Mountain
to do
Retreat r
r just break your foot a few
times it saves a lot of
time and it saves a lot of meetings with
strange
creatures you see I told me there was a
big creature outside my retri diam
Mountain the first night we went
there like 20 24 years
ago uh we stayed in tent each person
their own
tent and
uh was in a
[Music]
tent and this it was a cold pretty cold
night and there was a snake at the we
call Grand Grandpa's snake AB we call
him he's about four
me his body is like
this Ellie's asleep in the
tent she's
warm
this then a came on the other side of
the tent and she he snuggled up to
her she like you know and when stuff
happens to
you you have to say
great this will improve my compassion
for other people who meet
next okay so this is a new way of
looking at problems in your
[Music]
life you don't avoid them you
Embrace they call in English they call
character building
exercise having a big poisonous snake
snuggle up you is a character building
exercise
he used to come and watch me do yoga he
was
[Music]
unbelievable like I'm just doing yoga
man one day he one day uh he was out
with a rabbit in his
mouth and uh the way they eat
rabbit they sting the
rabbit and then they don't have teeth to
chew so they start with the leg you
know and they're
like you know slowly you
know then I did retreat with this very
brave
[Music]
lady
J what's her
name
Petra she she's she saw that snakes
swallowing the
rabbit she jumped out of her retree
cabin and said godamn and she pulled the
rabbit
away took it back to her
cabin and his leg was gone from the acid
the stomach
acid
and she fixed him up and he lived with
us for two
[Music]
years only just has three legs
you and he's fine and so anyway when
problems
happen when you break your
spine maybe it's the best thing that
ever happened to
you and as you reach the Golden Age of
70 or 80 I don't
know your opinion about disasters will
change you will say that was the best
thing that ever happened to
me so don't freak out when something bad
happens bodh uses
everything every accident every disaster
is a teach teaching from the
Budd relax and and and see what's the
teaching and your life will be very
cool all
right okay yep that's what he
said next p oh did we get the picture
from the last one oh yeah we did okay
second
picture credit card
problem maybe you met this
one by the way tomorrow I'm testing
you what was the guy with the
motorcycle sometimes disaster is the
best thing that ever happened to
you when you have emptiness
understanding you cannot say that the
accident was 100%
bad maybe it's the best thing that ever
happened to
you he he will say it's the best thing
that ever happened to him if he talk to
him now he will say
that he found out who his real friends
are and I I'm happy to say his his girl
you know his beautiful
girlfriend she's with
him and she took care of and they're
still
together it was so
beautiful then those other friends
disappear
right and so you find it's a good
thing all
[Music]
right uh the next sentence
says people like you and me
we think it would be better if good
things happen to us and disasters don't
happen to
us but he said that's not the way it
is then he quotes a
poem
is and
the teacher of this
book who was the teacher of my
teacher and maybe the greatest teacher
inet he quotes this
poetry and he doesn't tell you where
it's
from but luckily we have John
Brady and we have 12 million pages
and it's a it's a database I can check
this quotation in about three
seconds it will search 12 million pages
in three
seconds uh so here's the
meaning you should be unhappy when
things go
smooth
and you should be happy when things
screw
up
because when things are going smooth
you're burning up your good
karma so don't hope that things go
smooth because then you're going to burn
up all your good
car
but when you break your foot at the
airport you should be
happy you're burning up your Bad
Karma so when things go
smooth you should be
sad and when things f
up you should be
happy
K what's happening with your
foot I'm burning up Bad
Karma so
cool all right got
it how do you feel how how was
lunch it was
great but I just burned up a lot of good
karma I'm
sorry so what's going on with the credit
card
that lady is she went to go her
Retreat she's unhappy because all her
credit cards are paid
off and she doesn't have a chance to
burn up her Bad
[Music]
Karma you have to do the credit card
prayer
I hope the 28% interest rate gets higher
and
higher I can burn up so much bad
karma that's okay that's body stop
prayer I hope the electricity blows up
12 times
today
[Music]
Elric
I can burn up so many Bad
Seed all
right by the way there's there's Dharma
people who who talk like
that you know that I'm so happy oh J my
car broke down today I'm so
happy you know and you and me we we tend
to think they're a little bit you know
[Music]
cuckoo
don't don't be so
idealistic I mean don't take it too
far don't get happy every time you have
a disas it's just a book you
know but actually those people who take
it
l they are the Smart
Ones okay they they get they go go out
of this room and they feel so happy when
their car
breaks they are not The Crazy Ones We
Are The Crazy
Ones the normal people are The Crazy
Ones okay and those very you know I'm so
happy I BR my
car they are mentally
healthy Okay so let's try to be like
them when you have a serious problem in
your
life think about it you are burning up
bad
karma that's okay that's okay I can I
can take
it I'm
happy and and if you live as long as
Grandpa I'll tell you something when you
burn up a Bad
Karma
when you have a disaster in your
life it's very very common that the next
week or the next year is extremely
[Music]
happy you lose a Rel
relationship uh you lose a
job you know and then the next year is
like unbelievable
sweet you're free to have a better
relationship and you're free to find a
better
job and you burned off the bed
[Music]
C so when something seriously bad
happens to
you just be like I wonder what's coming
up
next this I've burned a lot of karma you
know so be
happy uh if you're
interested uh I found that uh poem in
the
database it comes from about 200 years
ago it's from uh a book called the dance
in the Lotus
Garden and and it's by a zen
master so Zen is another
tradition uh it's called great
completion it's a different tradition
than what we are
[Music]
doing and they have very beautiful
poetry and they don't understand
empty okay so you know and I'm not
critical I'm not
criticizing but but they don't really
understand
emptiness but the Poetry is very
beautiful okay so it's good it's
okay but
um you can get really good emptiness you
can get correct emptiness teachings at
a and they will make you happy for the
rest of your
life and
successful and you can sing rock and
roll songs off key and 6,000 people will
cheer okay that's emptiness okay power
of
emptiness you can sing bad music and
everybody thinks it's
great
that's real
empty all right